((我愛羅：俺は　お前を
友だと思っている。
かつての俺にとって
友とは　ただの言葉。
I consider you my friend.
それ以上でも
それ以下でもなかった。
In the past, "friend" was
merely a word to me.
だが　お前と会って
気づかされた。
Nothing more, nothing less.
大切なのは
その言葉の意味だと。
But after meeting you,
you made me realize that...
the meaning of that word
is what's important.
その意味するところが
なんなのか→
お前は　サスケのために
何をしてやれるのか。
What does it mean?
(よく考えろ))
What can you do for Sasuke?
♪～
Think hard about that.
《香燐：ダンゾウ…　いったい
どんな術を使うのか》
Danzo... Just what kind of
jutsu does he use?
《何！？　あの右腕！
W-What? That right arm...
写輪眼がいくつも！　キモイ！》
It has many Sharingan!
It's disgusting!
（サスケ）その右腕の眼はどうした。
How did you get those eyes
in your right arm?
（ダンゾウ）いろいろあってな。
話すと長い。
Through various means.
It would take too long to describe.
理由を聞いたところで
更に怒りが増すだけだ。
Any explanation would upset me more.
もういい。
お前は　殺すと決めている。
Forget it. I've decided to kill you.
その前に
聞いておきたいことが１つある。
Before that, let me ask one thing.
お前を含む
木ノ葉上層部の命令で→
Is it true that Itachi Uchiha eliminated
my clan by order of the Elders?
うちはイタチに　俺の一族を
抹殺させたのは　本当か！
This is...
《これは…》
So that’s Sasuke's...
《マダラ：ほう　あれがサスケの…》
So this is the Susano'o.
これが　スサノオというやつか。
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo mamoru yo
I'll keep you safe even though I don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
tsuyogatte bakari de namida wa misenai
You act tough, and never show any tears
hontou wa kowai kuseni
But I know you're scared
taisetsu na mono wo ushinawa nu you ni
You keep running so you don't lose what's important
hisshi de hashirinukete kita
We've always survived through the long night
itsu datte nagai yoru wo futari de norikoeta
I'll always be by your side
kono mama issho ni iru kara
So you don't need to act tough
tsuyogatte naide ii nda yo
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo susumu yo
We'll keep moving forward
even though we don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete sakenda
I'll scream up to the summer sky
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
Danzo's Right Arm
（ヤマト）で　これからどうします？
とにかく　いったん
木ノ葉に帰って→
So? What do we do now?
会談でのことを　里に
伝えなきゃならないと思いますし。
In any case, I think we should
return to the Hidden Leaf
サクラのことも…。
and report what happened
at the summit.
（サイ）サクラには
僕の本体がついています。
And also about Sakura.
サスケには　決して
近づかせません。
The real me is accompanying Sakura.
とりあえずは
安心してください。
She won't be allowed
to get near Sasuke!
（カカシ）とはいっても
直接行って　説得して→
You can count on that.
連れ戻したほうがいいでしょ。
But it would be better to go
in person and talk her out of it.
よし。
ヤマト　お前はナルトを連れて
里へ向かってくれ。
All right.
Yamato, take Naruto and
head back to the village.
俺は　サクラを連れ戻す。
サクラじゃ　サスケにかなわない。
死ににいくようなもんだ。
I'll bring Sakura back.
Sakura is no match for Sasuke.
会談の件は　忍犬たちを
すぐに走らせる。
It would be like
she’s going there to die.
急ぎだからな。
わかりました。
I'll dispatch the Ninja Hounds
with a report
about the summit since it's urgent.
サイ　サクラのところへの案内を頼む。
はい。
Understood.
Sai... Take me to Sakura.
♪～
Yes.
((ナルト：なんだってばよ　おめえら！
What the hell do you guys want?
（オモイ）お前たち
さっき　サスケの話をしてただろ。
You were just talking about Sasuke!
そいつの話を　聞かせろ！
Tell us what you were saying!
（サクラ）あんたたち雲隠れの忍に
なんの関係が　あんのよ！
It's got nothing to do with
you Cloud Ninja!
大ありだ！
It's got everything to do with us!
お前ら木ノ葉の　うちはサスケが
俺たちの里を襲った！
Sasuke Uchiha of the Hidden Leaf
attacked our village!
（カルイ）てめえらのとこの抜け忍
うちはが→
Your Rogue Ninja
abducted our master!
うちらの師匠を
連れ去りやがった！
師匠は生死不明だ　バカ野郎！
We don't even know if our master
is dead or alive, you idiots!
そ…　そんな…　ウソ…。
Th-That's a lie!
なんでサスケ君が　そんなことを！？
Why would Sasuke do such a thing?!
暁のやつらの目的なんて
知るかよ！
Like we'd know what
the Akatsuki's motives are!
暁って　どういうことだ？
The Akatsuki? What do you mean?
あぁ？　てめえ　ふざけてんのか？
Huh? Don’t kid around.
サスケは　暁の一員だろうが！
Sasuke is a member of
the Akatsuki!
お前らが
抜け忍を　野放しにしておくから→
You guys let your Rogue Ninja
roam free,
雷影様が　俺たちを遣わしたんだ。
so Lord Raikage ordered us
to come here!
うちはの始末の許可も
すでに　火影から　もらった！
And we've gotten your Hokage's permission
to get rid of the Uchiha!
《サスケが…　こいつらの師匠を…》
Sasuke abducted their master?
復讐は　させてもらう。
We'll get our revenge!
The Uchiha is ours!
(うちはは　うちらが倒す！))
♪～
Itachi Uchiha...
((うちはイタチ…。
His life was one of
personal sacrifice.
やつの生き様は
自己犠牲そのものだ。
For the village and more importantly,
for his younger brother.
里のため
そして　何より弟のために…。
Sasuke lost everything,
and he was left all alone,
サスケは　すべてを失い
１人になった…。
in exchange for peace
in Hidden Leaf Village.
木ノ葉の平和の代償が　それだ。
Can you still blame Sasuke?
そんなサスケを　責められるか？
Sasuke said that he couldn’t forgive
the Hidden Leaf
イタチの命を犠牲にして→
for sacrificing Itachi's life
to secure peace.
平和を満喫している
木ノ葉が許せないと　サスケは言った。
He is doing everything out
of a desire for revenge.
すべてが　復讐の対象だと…。
He is the real thing.
A true avenger.
本物だ…。
本物の復讐者だよ。
Hatred... It is Sasuke's Ninja Way!
(憎しみ…　それが　サスケの忍道だ))
くふっ！
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
The Hidden Leaf will deal
with Sasuke.
((サスケを　木ノ葉の手で処理する。
Every one of your comrades
is committed to that
and will act accordingly.
君の　同期メンバー全員が
そのつもりで動く。
Sakura is not a fool.
She’s not a child who
wouldn't understand
サクラは　バカじゃないし→
the difficulty of the situation.
それぞれの立場や状況が
わからないほど子供じゃないさ。
Sakura intends to
kill Sasuke herself.
(１人で　サスケを殺すつもりだな))
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
If you are prepared to bear
the burden of being a Kage,
((影の名を背負う覚悟を
決めたなら→
then do what is right as Sasuke's friend.
サスケの友として→
(お前が
本当に　やるべきことをやれ))
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
Naruto, is something wrong?
んっ？　ナルト　どうかしたのか！？
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
落ち着け　ナルト！
過呼吸だ。
息を　ゆっくりしろ！
Calm down, Naruto!
He's hyperventilating.
ナルト！
Breathe slowly.
ナルト　聞こえるか！
ナルト！
Naruto!
Naruto... Can you hear me? Naruto?
もう一度　問う！
I'm going to ask you
one more time.
お前を含む
木ノ葉上層部の命令で→
Is it true that Itachi Uchiha eliminated
my clan by order of the Elders?
うちはイタチに　俺の一族を
抹殺させたのは本当か！？
本当かと聞いてるんだ！
I'm asking if it's true!
さっさと答えろ！
Answer me!
あいつは　そんな男ではないと
思っていたが…。
I... I didn’t think he was
that kind of man.
イタチめ…→
Damn Itachi. I see he revealed
everything to you before he died.
死に際に
すべて　しゃべりおったか。
やはり　お前だけは
特別だったようだな。
As I thought...
It seems that you are truly special.
((マダラ：自分への復讐を
目的として与え→
By making revenge your goal,
he hoped to make you strong.
お前を強くすることを願った。
I acted like the older brother
you desired
（イタチ）お前が望むような兄を
演じ続けてきたのは→
in order to measure your vessel.
お前の器を確かめるためだ。
You will become a rival to
measure my vessel against.
お前は　俺の器を確かめるための
相手になる。
You have that hidden potential.
そういう可能性を秘めている。
You’ve been jealous of me
and resented me.
お前は　俺をうとましく思い
憎んでいた。
You’ve harbored hopes
of surpassing me.
この俺を超えることを
望み続けていた。
That is why I am allowing you
to live. For my sake.
だからこそ生かしてやる。
俺のために。
My foolish little brother...
愚かなる弟よ
この俺を殺したくば→
If you wish to kill me,
resent me, hate me.
恨め！　憎め！
And survive... in obscurity.
そして　醜く生きのびるがいい。
Run... keep running...
and cling to life.
逃げて逃げて
生にしがみつくがいい。
Then one day,
そして　いつか
俺と同じ眼を持って→
come before me with
the same eyes that I possess.
俺の前に来い！
The Uchiha is a proud clan
of the Hidden Leaf.
（マダラ）うちはは　木ノ葉隠れの里の
誇り高き一族だと→
He wanted you to keep believing that.
そう信じさせておきたかった。
He beseeched the Hokage
that you never learn the truth.
本当のことを
決して知られぬよう火影に願い→
And from the time he left the village,
里を抜けたときより
お前と戦い→
he was resolved to
fighting you and dying.
死ぬことを心に決めていたのだ。
You really have gotten stronger...
本当に強くなったな。　サスケ。
Sasuke.
So that he could instill in you
a new power.
（マダラ）そのとき　お前に
新しい力を与えるため→
He accepted disgrace
in the place of honor,
and hate in the place of love.
名誉の代償に　汚名を…
愛の代償に憎しみを受け取り→
And despite that, Itachi died with
a smile on his face.
それでも　なお
イタチは　笑って死んでいった。
He entrusted the Uchiha name to you,
his younger brother,
弟のお前に　うちはの名を託し→
deceiving you to the very end.
Lies! They’re all lies...
お前を　ずっと騙し続けたまま…。
Answer me!
I... I didn't think Itachi was the kind
of man who would reveal secrets.
(ウソだ！　そんなもの　すべて！))
どうなんだ！
あいつは…　イタチは…→
秘密をもらすような男ではないと
思っていたが…。
Does that mean it's true?
本当だったってことか！
自己犠牲…　それが忍だ。
Self-sacrifice...
That’s what epitomizes a shinobi.
日の目を見ることもなく
影の功労者…。
Never seeing the light of day.
Toiling in the shadows.
それが　昔からある　忍　本来の姿。
It is as it was in the past.
That is what a true shinobi is.
イタチだけではない！
多くの忍が
そうやって死んでいった。
It describes not only Itachi.
Countless other ninja have
died the same way.
世の中は
きれいごとだけでは回らん。
Niceties alone will not make
the world go round.
そういう者たちのおかげで
平和は　維持されてきたのだ。
Peace was attained all
because of people like him.
イタチの意思を　はき違えたお前には
わからぬだろうがな。
People like you who misunderstood
Itachi's intentions
couldn't possibly understand.
だが　お前に
秘密を明かしたイタチは→
Still... for Itachi to reveal such
a secret to you makes him
木ノ葉に対する裏切り…。
a traitor to the Leaf...
それ以上　イタチを語るな。
Don’t say anymore about Itachi!
そうだな…。
You’re right.
次は　眼で語る戦いにしよう。
Then let us proceed
to a battle of the eyes.
《どういうことだ！？
さっきので確実に死んだはず…。
What's going on?!
感知できるダンゾウのチャクラは
１つだけ…。
He should've died earlier!
影分身じゃないのは　たしか》
I can only sense chakra
from one Danzo.
やはりか…　スサノオ…。
I'm certain it's not a clone!
As expected... Susano'o.
身を守るには　もってこいだな。
Just the thing to protect yourself.
攻撃力も…　申し分ない。
The power in its attack is as expected.
《また…
今のも影分身じゃなかった。
Again? So if that wasn't
a clone either...
だとしたら…　幻術か！？》
Is it genjutsu?!
《サスケの中の
チャクラの乱れは感じられないし…。
Sasuke's inner chakra isn't disturbed.
うちのチャクラも安定してる…。
And my chakra is calm.
サスケも　うちも
幻術にかかってるわけじゃない。
If neither Sasuke nor I am
under a genjutsu...
だとしたら…。
Then...
いったい　どんな術だ！？》
what kind of jutsu is this?
きゃあ！
天照！
ぐっ…　うおっ…。
Amaterasu!
スサノオに天照まで…。
Susano'o and even Amaterasu...
ダンゾウの能力を確かめるにしては
やりすぎだ…。
That's too much just to
test Danzo's power.
バテるぞ！
He'll tire himself out.
サスケ！　後ろだ！
Sasuke! Behind you!
風遁　真空玉！
Wind Style: Vacuum Bullets!
サスケ！
Sasuke!
《口寄せの術！》
Summoning Jutsu!
ほう…　新しい口寄せか…。
いつの間に…。
A new summoning jutsu?
When did he get that?
天照…　久しぶりに見た…。
Amaterasu. It's been a while
since I last saw that.
やはり　イタチの弟だな。
You are Itachi's younger brother after all.
イタチの術を受け継いだか…。
You’ve taken over Itachi's jutsu.
お前が　イタチを語るな
と言ってるんだ！
I told you never to
speak of Itachi again!
兄弟…　能力は同じとて→
Brothers with the same ability.
Yet, what your eyes perceive
is so different.
眼が悟るものは
こうも違うものか…。
The truth about Itachi
isn't important to you.
お前にとってイタチの真実など
さほど重要ではない。
憎しみを手当たり次第に
ぶつけたいだけだ！
You direct your hatred at whomever
you can lay your hands on.
You make the sacrifice of
the Uchiha Clan meaningless.
お前は　うちは一族の犠牲を
無駄にしている。
You have no right to talk
about the Uchiha!
お前に…
うちはを語る資格などない。
♪～
Wind Style: Vacuum Blast!
Sasuke!
This is...
No way!
It's useless.
風遁　真空波！
Th-This is...
♪～
Itachi?
te ashi tsunagareteru yo i'm like marionetto
My hands and feet are tied up, I'm Like a marionette
sonna no arienee yo ittai dounatteru yo
This is nonsense, What's going on?
tell me tell me who's the ruler? kiyasuku sawaruna
(Tell Me Tell Me) Who's the Ruler?
Don't put your hands on me
kikitakuneeyo mou kiben wa
I don't want to hear your false arguments anymore
kokkara sakiwa ore ga kimen da!
I'm in charge of my own life from now on
mienai kusari wo tachikire
Break the invisible chains
genkai sure sure dashikire
Test your limits
jibun de kachi toranakya
If you don't win it for yourself
darekano te ni watacchauze
Someone else will take it
stand up! saa mina reach out for liberty
Stand Up!! C'mon everybody Reach Out For Liberty
ima ga ugokidasu toki da
It's time to make a move
wake up! saa mina step up shite sakebe
Wake Up!! C'mon everybody Step Up and shout
oh yes we are the dreamer
run for your freedom
saki datsu mono nante nakutatte
Even though you don't have a reason
run for your freedom
yume no tobira kettobashite
Kick the door to your dream
so you better stand up!! saa mina reach out for liberty
(so you better) Stand Up!!
サスケ！
C'mon everybody Reach Out For Liberty
ima ga ugokidasu toki da
It's time to make a move
♪～
wake up! saa mina step up shite sakebe
Wake Up!! C'mon everybody Step Up and shout
oh yes we are the dreamer
run for your freedom
saki datsumono nante nakutatte
Even though you don't have a reason
run for your freedom
yume no tobira ketto bashite
Kick the door to your dream
fight for your freedom
Next Episode
これって…。
Why did you hand over your life for this child, Itachi?
まさか…。
He misinterpreted your intentions,
he charges ahead with only hatred as his rationale. He is a fool.
Look closely, Itachi, this is your one and only mistake.
無駄だ。
♪～
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: “The Forbidden Visual Jutsu”
The Forbidden Visual Jutsu
I will correct your mistake.
It is finally time for me to be
in charge of a mini-corner!
Now that I’m here,
I’m going to make sure you feel
the passion, the friendship, the sweat,
the struggle, the gutsiness—
Palm Heel Strike!
こ　これは…。
At least you got to appear
in the main story.
My situation’s getting worse and worse.
イタチ…！？
I’ll be taking this mini-corner.
I won’t let you do this by yourself.
もしもし　そこのあなた。
"Adorable Tenten"
If we’re doing a mini-corner,
たまには　空から日本を眺めてみる
というのは　どうじゃろう？
why not feature me,
a cute, strong, and popular...
Idiots! All of us have had
little screen time recently.
今回は　ちと趣向を変えて→
We’re all in the same situation.
Am I right or not?
東京都で最も標高の高い所に
住んでいる人を探しにいくぞ！
Guy Sensei...
Therefore...
I will give you a hot, young,
and awesome mini-corner.
へえ　おもしろそう！
じゃろ？　途中の山間部には→
I call it...
You just want to show off!
東京都とは思えん
秘境暮らしをする人たちが→
Who are you kidding?!
... me Might Guy, with overflowing youth
続々　登場するぞ。
going at a great ultra-super full swing,
will bring everyone...